开萝尔:在上一集的中
Carol: Previously on Growing Pains.
教练:各位记得明天把学习总结交上来,
Coach: Your term reports are due tomorrow,
但一定要用打字机打出来,
and they should be typed on a typewriter.
就是那种一张纸放进去然后它就会…….
You know that thing where you put the paper in and it goes....
辛迪:洛维特教练在这吗?
Cindy: Is Coach Lovett here?
迈克:不不!他刚好出去了,是去擦亮他的脑袋去了.
Mike: No, no, he stepped out for a minute to polish his head.
辛迪:我回家后会告诉他的.
Cindy: I'll have to tell him that when I get home.
迈克:什么?
Mike: What?
辛迪:他是我爸爸.
Cindy: He is my dad.
迈克:哦,天啊,天啊!
Mike: Oh boy, oh boy, oh boy.
温迪:嘿!辛迪,爸爸在哪?
Windy: Hey Cindy where is dad?
迈克:哦,天啊,
Mike: Oh boy, oh boy, oh boy....
天啊!虽然我认识他好多年了,但还是对他不太了解.
I mean after all this time I feel like I don't even know Lovett at all,
每天他离开学校以后,也有自己的生活,他都做些什么?
after he walks out of this building he actually has his own life.
他住在哪?他是不是还有其他很多漂亮的女儿呢?
I mean what does he do, where does he live?
教练:那个混蛋根本不听我的,所以这学期一结束,
Coach: The little gofer didn't even listen to me,
我还是要被解聘.
so as of the end of the semester I'm fired.
迈克:开萝尔,你看,
Mike: Carol, look this guy has really given me a lot and I just want a
那教练真的帮了我好多,现在我只是想回报他一下.
chance to give him something back.
迈克:洛维特老师是个好教练,他挺关心人的.
Mike: Coach Lovett is a good teacher, he cares.
校长:关心人那可不是他的工作,他的工作是赢得足球比赛.
Principle: But he is not paid to care, he is paid to win football games.
麦琪:迈克 ,开萝尔,
Maggie: Mike, Carol please lets go,
我们走吧!他们说要把你们抓起来.
they are talking about having you arrested.
迈克:对不起,妈妈,我既然参与了这件事,我就得坚持到底.
Mike: I'm sorry mom but I am in this thing and I am staying.
开萝尔:除非他们把我们打昏了,然后再拖走.
Carol: They will have to bash us over the head and carry out our limp bodies.
麦琪:杰森,你就不能劝劝孩子们吗?
Maggie: Jason will you please talk some sense into these kids?
只是:听着,孩子们,我想这事……
Jason: Look kids, I think that ummm...
麦琪:杰森,你在干吗?
Maggie: Jason what are you doing?
杰森:我也和他们一起静坐.
Jason: I'm sitting in!
人群:喔!不,他不能走!不,他不能走!
Crowd: Yeah!!Heck no he won't go!Heck no, he won't go!
麦琪:小心他们的脑袋,你们这些纳粹分子!
Maggie: Watch their heads you Nazis!!
麦琪:这次示威中被逮捕有杰森·西沃医生,他的女儿开萝尔·西沃,他的儿子迈克·西沃以及迈克的好友斯塔伯恩.
Maggie: Arrested in the demonstration were Doctor Jason Seaver, his daughter Carol Seaver, his son Mike Seaver and his friend, fellow student Stabone.
本:哇!我们全家都被逮捕了.喂!臭虫我也是刚刚看到,这真是太刺激了.臭虫,你等等,我另外接个电话.喂?是奶奶吗?是的,我也看到了,我现在除了震惊就是担心.
Ben: Wow, my family has been busted.Hello, yeah, stinky I just saw it too, it was fantastic, Oh hold on a second stinky, I have got another call.Hello, grandma?Yeah, I saw it too, I am shocked and embarrass too.
电视:左边报数,然后右边报数.
Television: Left 234, right 234.
教练:伊丽莎白,我们回来了,用力推,辛迪,快用力推!
Coach: Elizabeth, we are home Pump it, pump it, way to go Cindy.
辛迪:谢谢!
Cindy: Thanks!
教练:不久你也会和温迪一样瘦的,年轻人,
Coach: You will be slim like Wendy in no time.
我和你一般大的时候,根本就没有肉吃!
Young man, when I was your age, I didn't even have meat.
麦琪:这里现在有三十多个警察.
Maggie: Over 30 policemen have been there ...
辛迪:爸爸,快来看,
Cindy: Daddy, daddy, come quick, your school is on the news,
你学校上新闻了,学校里面到处是警察.
there are cops and everything!
温迪:嘿!爸爸,你们学校的学生被抓了!
Wendy: Hey dad your school is being arrested!
麦琪:问题的始于年轻人的天真无知,
Maggie: He answer to this question begins with teenage innocence, and na?
而争论的焦点是格拉汉姆·洛维特教练
ve......taking the center of the controversy is Coach Graham Lovett.
女儿:爸爸,上面在讲你!
Daughter: Daddy, it's about you!!
教练:好,我马上过来!哦,什么?是谁没把厕所的卫生纸换了?
The coach: All right I'll be right there. Oh what? Who didn't replace place the toilet paper?
妈妈:嘘!我刚刚把小孩哄睡了.
Mother: Hush.I just got the baby to sleep.
女儿:你快看!
Daughter: Look!
妈妈:哦,天呀!格拉汉姆,亲爱的,你快点来!
Mother: Oh my!Graham, honey get in here quick!
麦琪:在这里待了十二年后,这位尽职的人就要被解雇了.
Maggie: After 12 years this dedicated man has been terminated .
女儿:爸爸被解雇了?
Daughter: Dad has been fired?
女儿们:什么?
Daughters: What?
妈妈:是的,孩子们
Mother: All right, now kids!
女儿:那我也买不了胸罩了.
Daughter: Does this mean I can't get my braces.
教练:你们听我解释一下,这卷是空的,这卷是满的.
Coach: Let me explain something.This is an empty roll.And this is a full roll.
女儿:爸爸,不管你是不是被解聘了,我们都是爱你的.
Daughter: Dad, we love you, even if you have been exterminated.
本:好的,赫默叔叔,我会告诉他们你有多震惊和多伤心的.
Ben: Ok, Uncle Homer, I'll tell them you are stunned and saddened.
麦琪:这是我一生中最丢脸的一天.
Maggie: This was the most humiliating day of my entire life.
杰森:这是我一生中最兴奋的一天.
Jason: The most exhilarating day in my life.
迈克:是的,我也是.
Mike: Yeah, mine too.
斯塔伯恩:我得去把身上的虱子弄掉.
Stabone: I am going to get deloused on a regular basis.
开萝尔:我还被一个胖女人搜了身.
Carol: I was frisked by a fat woman.
杰森:但我还是为你们感到骄傲.
Jason: But I was very proud of all of you.
本:你们谁想和赫默叔叔谈会吗?
Ben: Does anyone want to talk to Uncle Homer.
麦琪:本,我们叫赫默的叔叔.
Maggie: Ben, we don't have an Uncle Homer.
本:这真是有趣!
Ben: Very funny!
杰森:你们今天真是获益非浅呀!
Jason: You guys haven't lived tell you have been strip searched.
麦琪:杰森,现在我能不能和你到厨房谈谈.
Maggie: Jason, may I have a word with you in the kitchen now.
本:波纳的爸爸妈妈在厨房.
Ben: Boner's parents are in there.
波纳:你说什么?
Boner: What did you say?
本:他们很生气,所以我就做了花生酱,
Ben: Yeah, they were really upset, so I made them a peanut butter,
还有果冻蘑菇三明治,做得我都要累死了.
Jelly and mushroom sandwich.I am bushed.
波纳:就说你们没有看到我,也不知道我去哪里了.
Boner: Say you don't see me, say you don't know me .
杰森:波纳,不用紧张,我会和你爸爸妈妈解释的.
Jason: Boner, it's all right, I'll just explain to your folks.
斯塔伯恩的父亲:你原来在这里,你这个小囚犯.
Stabone's Father: There you are, you little jail bird ...
斯塔伯恩的母亲:理查德,你没事吧?
Stabone's Mother: Richard, are you all right?
斯塔伯恩的父亲:从他生下来以后,他就一直有事.
Stabone's Father: He hasn't been all right since the day he was born.
杰森:西尔维斯特,等等,先生,我正想和你谈谈波纳呢!
Jason: Sylvester, wait, sir, I just want to say Boner...
斯塔伯恩的父亲:你还是什么都别讲了,快到车里去.
Stabone's Father: The less said, the better.Get your butt in the car, come on.
斯塔伯恩的母亲:以后不许你在跟迈克来往,
Stabone's Mother: You are no longer allowed to play with Mike.
现在就和他最后说声再见吧.
Take a minute and say your goodbyes.
波纳:迈克,我们明天见.
Boner: See you tomorrow, Mike.
迈克:再见,波纳.
Mike: Later Bone.
麦琪:杰森,我们去厨房.
Maggie: Jason, Kitchen now.
迈克:爸爸,过来我们一起研究一下我们下一步的计划.
Mike: Dad, Dad, come on, I have to plan our strategy here. What's next?
杰森:好的,不过我要等会才能把1960年那时的和平示威讲给你听,
Jason: Well, I'll tell you what we did back in the peace riots in the 1960'
先失陪了.
s...excuse me.
迈克:好的,明天等教练来学校时……
Mike: Ok I know, tomorrow when the coach is at school...
开萝尔:我们什么也不要做了,迈克.我已经腻了,我的手印也被取走了,还被拍了一张极丑的照片,现在学校又对我留校察看.你知道留校察看意味什么吗?
Carol: We are going to do nothing, Mike.I have had it.I'd have my
finger prints and a very unflattering mug shot taken,
and I have been suspended from
school.Do you know what all of that means
迈克:意味什么?
Mike: What?
开萝尔:这意味着我毕业的时候就不能拿到全优毕业生奖.
Carol: It means that when I graduate I won't be receiving the perfect
attendance awards.
迈克:哦,不!我都干了什么?
Mike: Oh no!What have I done?
麦琪:杰森,他们都被留校查看,
Maggie: Jason, they have been suspended from school and Carol's perfect
开萝尔的全优毕业生奖也泡汤了.
attendance award is ruined.
杰森:哦,不!我都干了什么?
Jason: Oh no!What have I done?
麦琪:杰森,有时你的幽默感是一种吸引人的品质,
Maggie: Jason, there are times I think your sense of humor is a very
但今天的去一点也不吸引人.
attractive quality.This is not one of them.
杰森:好吧,
Jason: Ok, what happened today Maggie was that our son,
今天的情况是我们的儿子,一位原来毫无责任感的人,
a boy who doesn't even know how to spell commitment, much less have one;
竟然会毫无私心的去帮助别人.
today he puts himself on the line completely not for himself,
而被帮助的是谁?而他要帮助的人竟是他以前讨厌的老师,
but to unselfishly help somebody else.
我想凭这一点我们就应该今天是多么美好的一天.
A teacher, one of his enemies, I think this has been a pretty good day.
麦琪:亲爱的,
Maggie: Honey, honey it never would have occurred to me to look at things
你的分析是我从未想到过的.
that way.
杰森:谢谢,那现在你又怎么想呢?
Jason: Thank you, now what do you think?
麦琪:我想你简直就是一派胡言!
Maggie: I think you are a raving nut-ball!
杰森:哦,麦琪,我可不是在胡说!
Jason: Oh, I am not raving Maggie!
迈克:难道马丁·路德·金也是个傻瓜?
Mike: And was Martin Luther, B.B.King a fool too.
开萝尔:哈哈哈哈!
Carol: AHHHH!!!
迈克:开萝尔是怎么想到这么疯狂的想法的?
Mike: Where does carol get these crazy ideas?
杰森:是遗传的结果.现在你也大了,
Jason: She inherited them.
就老实和你讲吧,你妈是个疯子.
You're old enough to finally be told, Mike your mother is wacko.
迈克:爸爸,你觉得我应该放弃吗?
Mike: Dad, do you think I should give up?
杰森:那你对这事业有信心吗?
Jason: Well, do you believe in this cause?
迈克:我不知道什么是事业,
Mike: I don't know about cause,
我只是觉得教练就这么失去工作是有点不公的.在德文伊中学里,
but I just think it is totally unfair for the coach to lose his job.
他是唯一一个人相信我的老师.
I mean that all the teachers at Dewy,
爸爸,
he is the only one who believed in me.
我只是相帮帮他.教练,
Dad, I just want to help the coach.
你刚刚看电视了吗?
Oh coach, did you see we were just on television?
教练:西沃,你怎么不直接杀了我?
Coach: Seaver, why didn't you just shoot me?
杰森:教练,你等会说,你知道这孩子都为你做了什么吗?
Jason: Hold on there Coach, do you know what this kid did for you?
教练:是帮大忙了,
Coach: Golly, gee, heck, everybody knows what he did.
全世界都知道他做的事,
It was on the action news,
那可是头条新闻.
and how my kids found out their old man is being fired at the end of
连我的孩子们也都知道他们的爸爸将要被解雇了.
the year.
迈克:哦,教练,对不起!我……
Mike: Oh coach I am sorry I ...
教练:不用道歉,因为今年底我不会被解雇了.
Coach: Don't be sorry, 'cause I'm not beening fired at the end of the year any more.
迈克:好呀!
Mike: All right!
教练:不是的,教育局长看到这条新闻后打发雷霆,
Coach: No, you see superintendent Flagel,
于是就通知校长,接着校长就通知我叫我马上就走人.
he doesn't like his schools being on the news; so he called Dewitt,
真是谢谢你了,孩子!
and Dewitt called me, and he said I am gone as of today.Thanks kid.
女儿一:妈妈!
Daughter one: Mom!
母亲:谁?辛迪,是你,你什么事?
Mother: Yes?Cindy, yes, honey?
女儿:你在外面已经待了好久了.
Daughter: You've been out here for a long time.
母亲:是的,
Mother: Well, I am just waiting for your father to come home from driving
我只是担心你爸爸会不会到处乱开着车.
around aimlessly.
女儿:那你就到屋子里等吧!外面太冷了.
Daughter: Could you wait inside, it's cold.
母亲:你进去吧,我没事.
Mother: You just go back inside, I am fine.
女儿:你会生病的,你已经怀孕了.
Daughter: No you are not, you're pregnant.
女儿二:隔壁的尼格尔先生刚刚打电话过来说他也看到新闻里了,然后他就看到你站在那里,
Daughter 2: Mr.Nigel called from the next building, he saw the news,
他准备打911了.
and then saw you standing out here, he is ready to call 911.
母亲:好吧,谢谢他的好意,
Mother: Well, good golly to heck, pardon my French.
让他见鬼去吧!我跳之前会给你打电话的,
Before I jump I'll phone you, Mr.Nigel.
尼格尔先生.
Does a person have to be a loony tone just because they are out on their
难道我午夜穿着睡衣出来站在这里就是要自杀,他有必要大惊小怪的吗?
own fire escape in the middle of night in their pajamas?
一个女儿:妈妈,雪莉打我!
One daughter: Mom, sherry hit me!
另一个女儿:我就要打你!
Another daughter: And I enjoyed it!
母亲:别吵醒婴儿!
Mother: Don't wake the baby!
一个女儿:为什么我们不打开亮灯好让所有邻居都能看到我们家的好事?
One daughter: Why don't we just put up a spotlight so that the whole
neighborhood can enjoy our shame?
母亲:你看你已经吵醒婴儿了!
Mother: See, you woke the baby.
女孩:是他做的!
Girl: He did it!
男孩:不是我!
Boy: No I didn't!
教练:伊丽莎白,
Coach: Elizabeth, What the hell are you doing standing up there in your
你穿着这该死的睡衣站在这里到底想要干什么?
PJ's like some tart?
母亲:格拉汉姆,你是不是一直没戴帽子开车?
Mother: Graham, have you been driving around without your hat?
教练:什么?
Coach: What?
尼格尔先生:他说你是不是一直没戴帽子开车?
Mr.Nigel: She said you've been driving around without your hat?
母亲:谢谢你,尼格尔先生!
Mother: Thank you very much, Mr.Nigel
女儿:妈妈,你是在和一个酒鬼讲话!
Daughter: Mom, you are talking to a man who drinks wine for breakfast.
母亲:哦,是的,
Mother: Oh, all right you kids, your dad is home.
孩子们.你们爸爸回来了,
I want you all to go to your rooms.
我希望你们都会额=各自的房间去,看到这么多人他会更烦的.
He doesn't need to be reminded of how many of you there are.
女儿:你能不能叫爸爸不要在朝我们乱发脾气?
Daughter: Could you please try to keep dad from yelling and embarrassing
all of us?
教练:不,她不能.
Coach: No, she couldn't.
女儿:哦!
Daughter: Oh......
五个女儿:晚安,爸爸.
Five Daughters: Good night, dad.
男孩:晚安,爸爸.
Boy: Yo dad!
母亲:嘿,亲爱的,我跟你讲过多少次说开车时要戴上帽子吗?
Mother: Hi honey, and how many times I have told you to wear a hat?
教练:伊丽莎白,我们周围的这个世界现在这么乱,
Coach: Elizabeth, the world is crashing and burning around us,
而你却在关心我的帽子.
but you worry about my hat.
母亲:但是读者杂志上讲秃顶的人在冬天的时候要特别小心.
Mother: But the Digest said that the bald men have to watch out in the winter.
教练:戴了我还是光头,那有什么用?
Coach: Bald men have to watch out all the time, did you ever hear of birds?
母亲:那好,你就先坐这里吃些腊肠吧!
Mother: Ok, you just sit here and gnaw on your salami.
教练:我不知道努力工作了12年后怎么就突然被解雇?
Coach: I don't know, work hard, and you do a good job,
以后连腊肠也吃不到了.
and there is a budget cut, you lose the whole salami?
母亲:你还可以给弗洛伊德公司买药.
Mother: You can always sell medical supplies for Floyd's Company.
教练:你是不是又想叫你那白痴弟弟帮忙吗?
Coach: You didn't called that idiot brother of yours did you?
母亲:不不!我不会擅自决定的.
Mother: Oh no, no, no, no.I wouldn't do that without telling you first.
况且他也不在家,怎么能让你去推销药品呢?
Besides he wasn't home.What is all talk about selling medical supplies anyway?
你是一个老师,
You are a teacher and a good teacher, now remember,
一个好老师,一个好老师怎么能去推销痔疮药呢?
those who can't teach those who can't sell suppositories.
教练:亲爱的,我在那里干了12年,
Coach: Honey, I put in 12 years at that school, 12 years!
12年呀!
And what have I accomplished?
最后我得到了什么?为了教书那点钱你知道我失去了多少机会吗?
We sacrifice a lot to get by on that kind of money.
母亲:因为教书是上帝交给你的任务.
Mother: That is because teaching is a calling from god.
教练:也许这次他叫错号码了.
Coach: Maybe this time he called the wrong number.
怎么连一个孩子也没有来对我说"教练,
Has one kid ever walked up to me and said."
是你改变了我的人生"?或是说"老师,
yo coach, you made a difference in my life"? I'd settle for ..."
是你让我变得更优秀的"之类的话.
I'm better off for having known you."
母亲:我想你令我的生活更加有意义.
Mother: I am sure better off for having known you.
教练:亲爱的,你介意让我单独待会吗?
Coach: Honey, do you mind if I have a little bit of time alone out here,
让我好好想想下面该怎么办?
just to kind of sit and figure out what the point is for everything nowadays?
母亲:不过你要戴上你的帽子.
Mother: You will wear a hat?
教练:好的,我会戴上的,这下你看我的脑袋安全了.
Coach: Yes I will wear it, there you see the empire is safe.
母亲:格拉汉姆?
Mother: Graham?
教练:伊丽莎白,让我再多待一会吧!
Coach: Elizabeth, I think I need a little bit more time than that.
母亲:我想也许小哈维会帮你想到个好办法.
Mother: I thought maybe little Harvey here might just help you figure
out what the point it is nowadays.
教练:那么,哈维,
Coach: So, Harvey, what do you expect from this cock-eyed world, hum...?
你看我们现在应该怎么办?
I wouldn't mind clean diapers myself.What do you prefer, bottle or breast.
我不会介意自己清洗尿布的,你是喜欢奶瓶还是人奶.
Me too.
母亲:是的,你能不能帮我查到西沃家的电话号码?他们家是长岛的.
Mother: Yes.Do you have a number for the Seavers, in Long Island?
不,我不能大声讲的,这可是个秘密!
No I can't talk any louder, this is a secret.
迈克:我是不是很笨?
Mike: How stupid can I be?
杰森:开萝尔应该来回答这个问题的.
Jason: To bad Carol is not here to answer that.
迈克:嘿,爸爸.
Mike: Hi, Dad.
杰森:你在外面待了很久了.
Jason: You've been out here for quite a while.
迈克:是的,你介意晚上我在这里再多待一会吗?
Mike: Yeah look, if you don't mind I would kind or like to be alone tonight?
杰森:不,我不介意.
Jason: No, I don't mind.
迈克:爸爸,你坐在这里,我怎么能静下来呢?
Mike: Dad, How can I be alone if you are sitting out here with me?
杰森:迈克,你所做的并没有错.
Jason: Mike, what you did was not wrong.
迈克:爸爸,你看,
Mike: Dad, please look, if I didn't do anything,
要是我什么也没做的话,
the coach would still have his job tell the end of this semester,
教练至少还会教到这学期结束的时候,而开萝尔也有机会得到她那该死的优秀毕业生奖.
and Carol would still be winning her stupid perfect attendance awards.
杰森:迈克,
Jason: Mike, your mother was right;
你妈妈是对的.也许一开始我们就应该告诉你找校长谈话是很危险的事,
maybe we got carried away before you ever got into this I should have
要知道偷看注定不会有好下场的.
warned you that sometimes it can hut when you go to the wall for a principal.
妈妈,我们该听你的,
There is a downside to peeking in windows.
你明白我的意思吗?
We should listen to your mom, do you know what I am saying?
迈克:是的,你说妈妈听到你说她是个疯子.
Mike: Yeah, you are saying that mom heard you said that she was wacko.
麦琪:哦,这看起来很棒.
Maggie: Oh that looks great, Ben.
本:谢谢,现在我问你今晚谁要来做客?
Ben: Thanks, now please tell me who is coming over for dinner?
麦琪:是个秘密!等等,
Maggie: It's a secret.
你只排了12个位置,共有13个人,你得重新排一下.
Wait a minute, you've only set 12 places, its 13, now you have to redo it.
本:要不我就不吃了?我在说什么?
Ben: How about if I don't eat? What am I saying?
杰森:好吧,至少德威特先生是个通理的校长.
Jason: Well, at least Mr.Dewitt is an understanding principal.
迈克:通理?他要我留校察看,却只让我离开学校才一天.
Mike: Understanding?He cut my suspensions so I am only out of school one day.
开萝尔:离开一天?确一天的话我就不可能拿到优秀毕业生奖了.
Carol: One day?One day short of the perfect attendance record.
迈克:哦,太恐怖了.
Mike: Oh, the horror.
杰森:发生什么了?
Jason: What's going on?
麦琪:为什么你会觉得有事要发生?
Maggie: Why do you think there is something going on?
杰森:麦琪?
Jason: Maggie?
麦琪:哦,迈克,你能去开一下门吗?
Maggie: Oh, Mike would you answer that door?
迈克:好的.
Mike: Yeah.
教练的妻子:你一定是迈克了!哦!真高兴见到你.
Coach's wife: You are Mike.Oh!It is such an honor to meet you.
迈克:你是?
Mike: It its?
教练的妻子:哦,那你一定是开萝尔了,见到你真是……,麦琪.
Coach's wife: Oh you must be carol it is an honor to meet...Maggie...
麦琪:伊丽莎白.
Maggie: Elizabeth.
教练的妻子:哦,我们终于见面了.
Coach's wife: Oh, we finally meet in person!
麦琪:是的,你也怀孕了.
Maggie: Yes, you are pregnant!
教练的妻子:一直就没停过.
Coach's wife: Always.
麦琪:我也是.
Maggie: Me too.
迈克:你好!
Mike: Well, hello.
辛迪:迈克,好久不见了.
Cindy: Mike, long time, no see.
温迪:你都做什么?
Wendy: What are you doing?
辛迪:别挤我,温迪.
Cindy: Don't shove me, Wendy.
麦琪:你丈夫呢?
Maggie: Where is your husband?
教练的妻子:他在外面车里,他太顽固了.
Coach's wife: He is out in the car, he is so bullheaded.
迈克:女士们,我让你们一个一个来吻我吧.
Mike: Ladies, there is plenty of me to go around.
教练的妻子:听着,孩子们,
Coach's wife: Listen, kids, I have to talk to Maggie for a minute,
我要和麦琪谈会儿,玛丽,你来介绍一下吧!
so could you take over the introductions, oh...umm Marie?
玛丽:好吧,那个挺凶的是温迪,
Marie: All right, Wendy is the pushy one.Cindy is the over developed one.
那个有点胖的是辛迪,而话最多的是康尼.
The one in turmoil is Coney.
康士坦斯:我是康士坦斯.
Constance: Constance
梅丽:谁管你是谁,雪莉是那个矮点的.
Merry: No one cares.Sherry is the short one.Jerry is in the pants.
杰瑞是那个穿段裤的,这个刚尿湿衣服的是哈维.
Harvey is the one who just stained my blouse.
麦琪:我会把我以前用在杰森身上的窍门告诉你,那挺有用的.
Maggie: I could tell you tricks I used on Jason.It always works.
教练的妻子:哦,真的?
Coach's wife: oh really?
麦琪:杰森,我们在谈心.
Maggie: We are talking, Jason
杰森:你们是谁?
Jason: Who are you people?
麦琪:杰森,等会.
Maggie: Jason later.
杰瑞:那个穿套衫的小鬼是谁?
Jerry: Who is the fox in the weenie suit?
开萝尔:本,别理他,他是个坏蛋.
Carol: Ben, forget him, he's no good.
杰森:嘿!大家要不要饮料?本,你来招呼一下大家.
Jason: Hi, anyone want a soft drink?Ben, Take care of them.
麦琪:你可以做到的.
Maggie: You could do it.
教练的妻子:我可不想每周都去教堂忏悔.
Coach's wife: I just hate to lie with confessional week away
麦琪:不要把它当作是谎言,
Maggie: Well, don't think if it is a lie, Elizabeth, remember,
伊丽莎白你要记住这全是为了迈克和你丈夫和好.
the whole point of this is to get mike and your husband together.
教练的妻子:你讲得对,那我一会就来.
Coach's wife: You are right; ok please give me a minute.
教练:那么说迈克想向我道歉,那他自己为什么不到这里来?
Coach: So it Mike wants to apologize, Why doesn't he just come out here?
教练的妻子:亲爱的,这我不知道,但他正在厨房等你.
Coach's wife: Honey, I don't know, but he is waiting for you in the kitchen.
教练:你保证?他向我道歉后我们就回去.
Coach: Promise?If I let him apologize, we can go.
麦琪:洛维特教练想在厨房和你谈谈,
Maggie: Coach Lovett wants to have a word with you in the kitchen,
他想单独谢谢你.
and he wants to thank you man to man.
教练:什么事?
Coach: So!
迈克:什么事?
Mike: So!
教练:迈克,一个真正的男人就该好好认错.
Coach: Mike, it takes a real man to admit his mistakes.
迈克:你什么也不用讲了,很高心你能来,我们一起去吃……
Mike: You don't need to say any more, I am just glad you are here
Come on let's eat
教练:等等!我想我们在这里是为了道歉的.
Coach: Hold on, hold on, I believe we are here for an apology.
迈克:好吧,要是你想的话.
Mike: Ok, if that what you want.
教练:那就随便说一下什么"对不起"之类的话!
Coach: About two words like I'm sorry!
迈克:好的!你马上要说吗?
Mike: Great!You are going to say them soon?
教练:你想让我对你说对不起?
Coach: You expect me to say I'm sorry.
迈克:不,只要说谢谢就行.
Mike: No, just say thank you.
教练:我为什么要说谢谢你?
Coach: Why do I thank you?
迈克:我就是为了你才被逮捕的!
Mike: Well I did get arrested for you!
教练:你让你这么做的?
Coach: Who asked you to?
迈克:没人.
Mike: Nobody.
教练:现在我已经失业了,
Coach: And now that I am out of work,
你还想继续帮我喂饱这些孩子吗?
are you going to help me keep those mouths filled?
你能帮我向康士坦斯解释一下她不能买胸罩的原因吗?
And are you goin to explain to my Constance why she cannot have her braces?
还有你能帮我将另外的65份简历发出去吗?
And are you going to help me send out another 65 resumes?
迈克:教练,我也不想你被解雇啊.
Mike: Look, coach, I didn't mean if you did get fired.
教练:我可不愿到最后自己和七个半孩子要一起挨饿,以前我觉得教师是永远不会失业的,
Coach: And I didn't mean to end up with 7 and two thirds kids and no income,
但我想错了.
nada, zip.I always figured that a teacher could always get a job.Not any more.
65个学校里只有一个学校要我,
There are 65 schools, one offered me a job.
而且钱也很少,学校又是在加州,
But I earn less money, in California.I'd have to buy a toupee.No thanks.
我还得买假发套.我不能去那里教书,
I would rather call my brother-in-law and go to work with him pushing
我宁肯去找我那个小舅子帮他卖痔疮药.
suppositories.
迈克:教练,我只是想报答你.
Mike: Coach, I only want to pay you back.
教练:报答我什么?我不知道,不过你已经为我做了很多.
Coach: Pay me back for what?I don't know, you've done a lot for me.
教练:你说我为你做了很多,
Coach: When you say I have done a lot for you,
是不是意味着你更加了解我?
does that mean anything like your better off having known me?
迈克:我无法用具体的话语形容.
Mike: I mean I wouldn't use the exact words.
教练:不过你是不是想说……
Coach: Well but ......something like that?
迈克:是的,我想你确实令我更加了解你.
Mike: Yeah, I guess you could say that I am better off having known you.
杰森:麦琪,我能一起帮你准备晚餐吗?
Jason: Maggie is there something I can do to help get this dinner going?
麦琪:杰森,还有重要的事要在晚餐上讲.
Maggie: Jason, there are more important things going on then dinner.
杰森:有四个小孩都快要饿晕了.
Jason: Four children just fainted over here.
麦琪:哦,看谁在那!
Maggie: Oh, look who is here!
本:开饭了!
Ben: Dinner!
麦琪:哦,再过一会就开饭.
Maggie: Oh, it will just talk a a second to get the dinner.
教练:等等!各位在开始吃以前,
Coach: Hold on, hold on, everybody before we start to eat tonight,
先听我讲几句心里话.我想要为我以前的胡话向你们道歉,
I just like to say a few words from the heart.
我就不拐弯抹角了.
I just want to apologize for all the sewage I have been pumping lately.
就直接一点吧!我现在心里满是……
I mean why beat around the bush.Let's face it.I have been full of ...
教练的妻子:你讲得真好!
Coach's wife: That was a very nice speech.
教练:还没有讲完呢!我要讲的要点是,
Coach: I've not done.
我本来已经绝望了,
You see the point I make that is I was ready to give up.
本来以为我一辈子一事无成了,
I couldn't see how anything I have done mattered,
以为教书也毫无意义,可是过去我不是这样的
and I couldn't see how teaching mattered, and you know it wasn't like that?
孩子们:在我还是小孩的时候……
Kids: When I was growing up...
教练:并非这样的.那时人们都很尊敬老师,
Coach: It wasn't.People respected the teachers,
社会的不良现象也很少.在家也会很有安全感,
and there wasn't all the damn graffiti all over the place.
人人都会自力更生,
And you could feel safe in your own home.
即便是不太爱劳动的人也是一样.对不起,
And family stood up for their own even if they were not particularly find
伊丽莎白,我并非有意讲到你的弟弟.
of them, and I am not talking about your brother, Elizabeth.
教练的妻子:我以为你已经答应我不再说他的.
Coach's wife: I think you promise us a point.
教练:是的,
Coach: Yeah, here it is.
我还要说这世界上还是有很多好人,
The point is there are still a lot of people in this world that care.
这两张桌上的人就是最好的例子.开萝尔,
And these two tables are full of them.
谢谢策划了静坐示威的事,
Carol, thanks for help organize the sitting in.
为了我你的确做了很大的牺牲.
you've really put you behind on the line for me.
开萝尔:哦,那没什么.迈克,你给我闭嘴.
Carol: Ah that was nothing.Shut up Mike
教练:另外,西沃太太,谢谢你和伊丽莎白一起准备这次晚餐.
Coach: And Mrs.Seaver.Thank you for working out this dinner with Elizabeth.
麦琪:那没关系,不过是加八个位置而已.
Maggie: It was no problem.I only set 8 other places.
本:难道是你摆的桌子.
Ben: You set the table?
教练:还有西沃医生,谢谢你要求迈克静坐以坚持他的信念.
Coach: And doctor Seaver, thanks for teaching Mike to sit down for what he believes
in
杰森:我会为他感到骄傲的.
Jason: Pleasure was all mine.
教练:迈克,
Coach: And Mike thanks for reminding me,
是你让我明白作为一名教师的意义,使我没有放弃这份职业,
why I became a teacher and why I can't give it up.
我该怎么谢谢你呢?
How can I ever thank you?
迈克:好了,那你能不能嫁一对女儿给我?
Mike: Well, could you spare a couple of your daughters?
教练:不可能.
Coach: Not a chance.
迈克:那你就当我没讲过吧!
Mike: I never would have forgave myself if I didn't ask .
教练:最后我要谢谢伊丽莎白,
Coach: And one last thing I'd like to thank my Elizabeth for being a major
感谢你这样甘心和我一起吃苦.
pain in the butt.
教练的妻子:哦,格拉汉姆,我会一直在你的身边的.
Coach's wife: Oh, Graham, any time.
教练:孩子们,我太爱你们了.
Coach: And kids you know how I feel about you.
男孩:我们也爱你,你这个大脑袋的男人.
Boy: Well we love you too, you big dump chuckle head.
孩子们:哦,爸爸!无论发生什么,我们都会支持你的.
Kids: Oh dad!Whatever happens we will be behind you all the way .
教练:谢谢!我想你们在加利福尼亚会过得很好的,快吃吧!
孩子们:加利福尼亚?不……
00:22:58,500
Coach: Thanks, thanks, I know we'll do just fine in California.Let's eat. Kids: California?No.....